AKSHAY HORE

Chicago, Illinois | +1 (773) 664-4072 | ahore3@uic.edu | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Experienced Java and SAP ABAP developer with 3 years of information technology professional work in SDLC environment and stronghold on programming using object-oriented principles extend with RDBMS. Proven skills in designing, developing, and testing with an understanding of coding standards and practices.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages and Frameworks: Java, Java EE, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML 5, CSS3, PHP, SQL, SAP ABAP, Python, Spring, Hibernate, JDBC Software: Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, Android Studio, Git, Tableau, Jupyter Notebook, SAP GUI, SQLiteStudio, MS Office Databases: MS SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, SQLite

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Infosys. Pune, MH, India

Clients: Zoetis Inc. and McKesson Corporation.

Senior System Engineer

May 2021 - Jul 2021

SAP ABAP Developer

- Implemented OOP concept in functional programmed SAP Reports that increased overall code execution speed by 25%.
- Enhanced classical reports with dialog programming and interactive methods, resulting in an increase in client KPI by 100%.
- Executed trace mapping and performance optimization coding that resulted in the reduction of program run time by 20%.
- Designed add-on functionalities for SAP reports to export output files over E-mail, reduced discrepancy from 20% to 1%.
- Improved design and implementation for report programs based on client feedback and boosted accuracy by 15%.
- Coordinated in modules such as OTC, P2P, SD, FI, and MM to automate the business that cut down paperwork by 70%.

System Engineer Jan 2019 - May 2021

Java Software Developer

- Created programs using REST APIs, Microservices and Data processing algorithms led to a 25% increase in project productivity.
- Rendered solid technical expertise in Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) with Agile and Waterfall Methodologies.
- Built programs using Multithreading, File Handling I/O and Data Structure Programming with speed increased by 30%.
- Developed frontends using JavaScript, HTML and CSS integrated backend using servlets with 15% reduced wait time.
- Diagnosed codes with Postman to test existing APIs which reduced discrepancy from 35% to 2% in pre-production.
- Prepared Queries for Database implementation with JDBC using MySQL and SQLite Studio, reducing picking time by 60%.
- Developed code in Java EE environment for developing test cases with JUnit and logging using Apache Log4j.
- Enhanced the quality of code and improved application performance, reducing bugs by 15% and lessened client complaints.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois Chicago, IL, USA **Master of Science in Management Information Systems** Aug 2021 - May 2023

GPA: 3.8/4

Key Learnings: Enterprise Application Development (Java), Advance DBMS (MySQL), Cybersecurity, Statistics, Data Visualization (Tableau), Data Mining (R), Operation Management.

Vishwakarma Institute of Information Technology, Pune, MH, India Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Telecommunication

Aug 2014 - May 2018

Percent: 67.8%

ACTIVITIES

Award: "Best Project Award for Bachelor of Engineering 2018" at Pune University.

Leadership: Event Coordinator and Technical Head for IEEE National Conference at VIIT.

Aug 2015 - Aug 2017

Languages: Fluent in English, Marathi, and Hindi.